這孩子跟我走
The kid's coming with me.
《曼達洛人》前情提要
他在追蹤誰
Who's he tracking?
孩子
The kid.
他們不會罷休的
Then they’ll keep coming.
嗯
Yes.
星球大戰
曼達人
Mando.
那桶似的頭盔下面是你嗎
Is that you under that bucket?
蘭恩
Ran.
我都不確定
I didn't really know
是否還能在這一帶見到你
if I'd ever see you in these parts again.
見到你真好
Good to see you.
說實話
You know, to be honest,
你和我聯系時  我還有點吃驚呢
I was a little surprised when you reached out to me.
因為我...  有所耳聞
You know, 'cause I... I hear things.
好像你和公會搞僵了
Like, maybe things between you and the Guild aren't workin' out.
我不會有事的
I'll be fine.
好吧  你知道規矩
Okay. Well, you know the policy.
不該問的不問
No questions.
而你呢  隨時歡迎你回這里
And you, you're welcome back here anytime.
是什么活
So, what's the job?
我們的一個手下和競爭者
Yeah, one of our associates ran afoul of
起了爭執  人被抓起來了
some competitors and got himself caught.
我在組建個團隊去救他
So, I'm puttin' together a crew to spring him.
五個人的活  我這有四個人
It's a five person job. I got four.
我需要的是交通工具  而你開來了
All I need is the ride, and you brought it.
飛船不包括在這單生意里
The ship wasn't part of the deal.
我允許你回來都是因為刀鋒之巔
Well, the Crest is the only reason I let you back in here.
什么表情
What's the look?
是感恩嗎
Is that gratitude?
我感覺是
Uh-huh. I think it is.
梅菲爾德
Hey, Mayfeld.
干嘛
Yeah?
這是我和你說過的那個曼達人
This is Mando, the guy I was tellin' you about.
我們曾一起干事  那還是...
We used to do jobs way back when...
就是他啊
This is the guy?
嗯  那時我們都血氣方剛  想要揚名立萬
Yeah, we were all young, tryin' to make a name for ourselves.
可和一個曼達洛人闖蕩  那...
Yeah, but runnin' with a Mandalorian, that was...
那確實讓我們有了點名氣
That brought us some reputation.
是嗎  那對他有什么好處
Oh, yeah? What did he get out of it?
我曾經問過他  你還記得你怎么回答的嗎
I asked him that one time. You remember what you said, Mando?
打靶練習
Target practice.
我們做過些瘋狂事  是不是
We did some crazy stuff, didn't we?
那是很久以前的事了
That was a long time ago.
是啊...
Well...
我不去外面折騰了  你明白嗎
Well, I don't go out anymore. You understand?
所以這個事由梅菲爾德負責
So, uh, Mayfeld, he's gonna run point on this job.
他下的命令就等于是我下的
If he says it, it's like it's comin' from me.
你沒問題吧
You good with that?
我不知道
You tell me.
你一點都沒變
You haven't changed one bit.
這里的情況已經不同了
Yeah, well, things have changed around here.
梅菲爾德  他...
Yeah, well, Mayfeld, he's...
他是我見過的最棒的槍手
He's one of the best triggermen I've ever seen.
前帝國的神槍手
Former Imperial sharpshooter.
那也沒什么光彩的
That's not saying much.
我不是暴風兵  自以為是的家伙
I wasn't a stormtrooper, wiseass.
夠快的  是吧
Don't take long, does it?
刀鋒之巔  這玩意還能飛啊
Razor Crest? I can't believe that thing can fly.
看著就像坎托拜那里的老虎機一樣
Looks like a Canto Bight slot machine.
那個長角的帥哥叫伯格
The good-lookin' fellow there with the horns, that's Burg.
你可能想不到  他是我們的打手
This may surprise you, but he's our muscle.
這是個曼達洛人
So, this is a Mandalorian.
我以為他們是大塊頭呢
I thought they'd be bigger.
機器人叫零
Droid's name is Zero.
你不是說你有四個人嗎
I thought you said you had four.
沒錯
He does.
你好  曼達人
Hello, Mando.
希安
Xi'an.
給我個理由不就地把你砍翻在地
Tell me why I shouldn't cut you down where you stand?
見到你我也很高興
Nice to see you, too.
我挺想你
I missed you.
這真亮啊
This is shiny.
你穿著不錯
You wear it well.
我們是不是應該回避一下
Do we need to leave the room or something?
曼達人離開我們的團隊以后
Well, Xi'an's been a little heartbroken
希安有點傷心
since Mando left our group.
你會沒事吧  寶貝
Aw. You gonna be okay, sweetheart?
我現在很一本正經的
Oh, I'm all business now.
從最好的師傅那學來的
Learned from the best.
好吧  小情侶
All right, lovebirds.
等我們上了飛船你們再膩味吧
Break it up till you get on the ship.
現在我們沒時間
Right now we don't have much time.
真小
Tiny.
曼達洛人
第一季  第六集
囚犯
燃料
Fuel.
導航  曲速
Navigation. Hyperdrive.
起落架
Landing gear.
通訊裝置
Comms.
曼達人
Mando...
我得到了好消息
I received... I received wonderful news.
在你...你的...  遞交獵物...
Upon your... Upon your... Deliver the quarry. Deliver the...
目標正在一艘被加固過的運輸飛船上
So, the package is being moved on a fortified transport ship.
我們只有很短的時間可以登機  找到我們的朋友
Now, we got a limited window to board, find our friend,
在他們進入曲速之前救出他
get him out of there before they make their jump.
這是新共和國的監獄船
That's a New Republic prison ship.
你的人不是被對立集團帶走了  而是被逮捕了
Your man wasn't taken by a rival syndicate. He was arrested.
那又如何
So what?
你已經接下任務了
A job is a job.
這是最高安全級別的運輸艦
That's a max security transport
我不想惹這種麻煩
and I'm not looking for that kinda heat.
我們也不想  所以別搞砸
Well, neither are we. So just don't mess up.
好消息是  這艘飛船是由機器人操控的
The good news for you is the ship is manned by droids.
你還是很討厭機器  對嗎  曼達人
Still hate the machines, Mando?
雖然最近進行過修整
Despite recent modifications,
這艘飛船的情況還是一團糟
the ship is still quite a mess.
輸電線在漏電  導航系統斷斷續續
The power lines are leaking, the navigation is intermittent,
曲速的運行效率只有67.3%
and the hyperdrive is only operating at 67.3% efficiency.
我們有更好的飛船  為什么還要用這一艘
We have much better ships. Why are we using this one?
因為刀鋒之巔已經脫離了
'Cause the Razor Crest is off
老帝國和新共和國的監控范圍
the old Imperial and the New Republic grid.
就是一艘影子飛船
It's a ghost.
沒錯  我們需要一艘可以足夠接近監獄船
Yeah, and we need a ship that can get close enough
并且干擾新共和國暗碼的飛船
to jam New Republic code.
當我們在這里脫離曲速
So, when we drop out of hyperspace here,
我們會立刻達到到這里的海拔
if we immediately bank into this kinda attitude,
應該可以直接進入他們的盲點
we should be right in their blind spot,
這可以給我們爭取足夠的時間
which will give us just enough time
來讓你的飛船隱藏我們的信號
for your ship to scramble our signal.
這不可能  連刀鋒之巔也做不到
It's not possible. Even for the Crest.
所以才要他來駕駛
That's why he's flyin'.
曼達人  我知道你是個很優秀的飛行員
Mando, I know you're a pretty good pilot,
但我們需要你執行任務  而不是駕駛飛船
but we need you on the trigger. Not on the wheel.
別擔心  曼達洛人
Don't worry, Mandalorian.
我的反應時間比有機生命體更快
My response time is quicker than organics.
而且我更聰明
And I'm smarter, too.
好了  可以了
All right. I-- Yeah. That's good.
請原諒  他的程序還是有些不完善
Forgive the programming. He's a little rough around the edges.
但他確實是最出色的
But he is the best.
你怎么能相信它
How can you trust it?
你了解我  曼達人  我不相信任何人
You know me, Mando. I don't trust anybody.
就像過去的美好時光  曼達人  對嗎
Just like the good old days, Mando. Huh?
你能坐下嗎
Will you sit down?
計算完成
Calculations complete.
現在開始進入曲速
Jumping to hyperspace now.
你可以和他們會合了  后面交給我
Feel free to join the others. I will handle it from here.
好了  好了  我明白
Hey, hey, hey. Okay. Okay. Okay, I get it.
我對私人空間也很敏感
I'm a little particular about my personal space, too.
我們做任務就好
So, let's just do this job.
進去  出來
We get in, we get out,
然后你也不必再見到我們了
and you don't have to see our faces anymore.
告訴我  我們為什么需要曼達洛人
Someone tell me why we even need a Mandalorian.
很顯然  他們是星系最勇猛的戰士
Well, apparently they're the greatest warriors in the galaxy.
別人是這么說的
So they say.
那他們怎么都死了
Then why are they all dead?
你和他一起飛行過  希安
Well, you flew with him, Xi'an.
他和他們說的一樣厲害嗎
Is he as good as they say?
問問他阿爾佐克三號星上的任務
Ask him about the job on Alzoc III.
我做了我必須做的事
I did what I had to.
但你很享受
Oh, but you liked it.
我知道你到底是什么人
See, I know who you really are.
他從沒摘下過頭盔嗎
He never takes off the helmet?
此乃正道
This is the Way.
我很好奇你到底長什么樣
I wonder what you look like under there.
也許他是岡根人
Maybe he's a Gungan.
難道這就是你不愿意露臉的原因
Is that why yousa don't wanna show your face?
你見過他的臉嗎
You ever seen his face?
女人從不泄密
A lady never tells.
曼達人  我們得互相信任
Aw. Come on, Mando. We all gotta trust each other here.
你總得讓我們見識見識
You gotta show us somethin'.
來吧  把頭盔抬起來
Come on. Just lift the helmet up.
來吧
Come on.
讓我們看看你的眼睛
Let's all see your eyes.
我來
I'll do it.
那是什么
Whoa! What is that?
你在這很寂寞嗎  小家伙
You get lonely up here, buddy? Huh?
等等  這是你們倆生的嗎
Wait a minute. Did you two make that? Huh?
這是什么  寵物嗎
What is it, like a pet or somethin'?
是的  差不多
Yeah. Something like that.
沒看出來你是這種人
Didn't take you for the type.
也許是你的準則讓你心軟了
Maybe that code of yours has made you soft.
我從來就不喜歡寵物
Me, I was never really into pets.
我沒那個耐心
Yeah, I didn't have the temperament. Patience, you know?
我試著養過  也沒什么結果
I mean, I tried, but never worked out.
但我在考慮
But I'm thinkin'
也許我可以試著再養一次這個小家伙
maybe I'll try again with this little fella.
現在開始脫離曲速
Dropping out of hyperspace now.
現在開始最終著陸
Commencing final approach, now.
現在開始隱蔽信號
Cloaking signal, now.
現在準備對接
Engaging coupling now.
對接確認  我們落地了
Coupling confirmed. We are down.
放松
And relax.
開始營救任務
Commence extraction now.
廢物機器人甚至都沒給我們認真倒計時
Useless droid didn't even give us a proper countdown.
零  你確定他們看不到我們嗎
Z, are you sure they can't see us?
刀鋒之巔擾亂了我們的信號
The Razor Crest is scrambling our signature
我入侵進了監獄系統
and I am inside the prison system.
這艘炮艦居然幸存了下來
It's impressive that this gunship had survived the Empire
沒有被帝國扣押  真是太厲害了
without being impounded.
好了我們有工作要做  曼達人  該你了
All right, we got a job to do. Mando, you're up.
-是我嗎  -一直都是你
- It's me? - Always you.
零
Zero.
帶我們去控制室
Get us to the control room.
向下三層  正在關閉艦內監控
Sub level three. Disabling onboard surveillance.
好吧  我們時間緊迫
All right, we're on the clock.
當我們和那些機器人交戰時  它們會一擁而上
When we engage those droids, they're gonna be all over us.
我知道這個套路
I know the drill.
生物追蹤器激活
Bio trackers activated.
我有眼睛
I've got eyes.
好吧  我們走
All right, let's go.
-我不喜歡這個感覺  -你總是多疑
- I don't like this. - You always were paranoid.
是真的嗎  曼達人  你總是多疑嗎
Is that true, Mando? Were you always paranoid?
接近控制室  在下一個路口向左拐
Approaching control room. Make a left at the next juncture.
怎么了  只是個小老鼠
What? It's just a little mousey.
-過來  小老鼠  -伯格
- Come here, little mousey. - Burg.
不  伯格  你在干什么
No! Burg, what are you doin'?
怎么了
What?
入侵者警報  開火
Intruder alert. Open fire.
我們這里太暴露了
We're too exposed here.
如果他們發出信號  那就沒關系了
If they get a signal out, it's not gonna matter.
曼達人  上啊  你應該是個狠角色
Mando, let's go! You're supposed to be somethin' special.
我就知道  我就知道
I knew it. I knew it!
記得把你的爛攤子收拾干凈
Make sure you clean up your mess.
看來你們的存在被發現了
It seems your presence has been detected.
將安全警報從你們的位置重移開
Redirecting security alert away from your position.
零  開門
Z, open the door!
但我發現了一個有機體信號
But I'm detecting an organic signature.
行了知道了  把門打開
Yeah, okay. All right. Just open the door!
站住
Stop!
就停在那兒
Just stop right there.
立刻放下槍
You put down the blasters right now.
鞋子不錯
Nice shoes.
放下你的槍
Put down your blasters.
跟他的腰帶很配啊
Matches his belt.
這艘艦上應該只有機器人的
There were only supposed to be droids on this ship.
等等  等等  我們看看
Hang on, hang on. Let's see here. Uh...
二二一號房
Cell two-two-one.
好吧  現在給我們穿著考究的朋友
All right, now for our well-dressed friend.
慢著慢著  放松  蛋頭
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey, hey. Easy. Easy, egghead.
把它放下  把它放下  快點
Put that down. Put that down. Come on.
放松  快放下
Easy. Put it down now!
放松  不用有人受傷  冷靜
Easy. Nobody has to get hurt here. Just calm down.
那是什么東西
What is that thing?
這是一個跟蹤信標
It's a tracking beacon.
他按那個鍵  我們都得死
He presses that thing, we're all done.
新共和國的攻擊群會循跡而來
A New Republic attack team will hone in on that signal
把我們炸成渣
and blow us all to hell.
放下它
Put it down!
你是認真的嗎
Are you serious?
是的  我是認真的
Yes, I'm serious.
你以為我們不需要知道那個小細節
You didn't think we needed to know that tiny little detail?
我沒想到我們會走到這一步
I didn't think we'd get to this point.
但我們確實走到了
Yet here we are.
你在質疑我的管理風格嗎  希安
Are you questioning my managerial style, Xi'an?
沒有  長官
No, sir.
嘿  聽我說
Hey. Listen to me.
嘿  聽我說  好嗎
Hey, hey, hey. Listen to me, okay?
聽我說
Look.
-嘿  把槍放下  -你瘋了嗎
- Hey. Put it down. - Are you crazy?
放下槍
put it down.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
-我是達文  -達文
- It's Davan. - Davan.
我們不是來抓你的  我們是來救犯人的
We're not here for you. We're here for a prisoner.
如果你讓我們完成任務  你可以活著離開
If you let us go about our job, you can walk away with your life.
不  他不會的
No, he won't.
你知道你會給我們帶來什么嗎
You realize what you're gonna bring down on us?
你覺得我在乎嗎
You think I care about that?
我們不會殺人  懂嗎
We're not killing anybody, you understand?
把槍從我臉上拿開  曼達人
Get that blaster out of my face, Mando.
我不能那樣做
I can't do that.
把槍從我臉上拿開  曼達人
Get that blaster out of my face, Mando!
不要
Don't.
你們都閉嘴好嗎
Would you both just shut up?
瘋狂的老提
Crazy Twi.
我剛才控制住局面了
I had it under control.
真棒  看起來控制住了
Yeah. Looked like it.
那東西以前在閃嗎
Was that thing blinking before?
有嗎
Was it?
-零呼叫梅菲爾德  -怎么了
- Zero to Mayfeld. Zero to Mayfeld. - What?
我發現你們的位置上
I've detected a New Republic distress signal
有一個新共和國求救信號
homing in on your location.
你大概有20分鐘
You have approximately 20 minutes.
我們只需5分鐘
We only need five.
我們走  快  快  快
Let's go, let's go. Move, move, move!
零  打開
Z, open it up.
-你還有15分鐘  -快點  快點
- You have 15 minutes remaining. - Come on, come on.
打開
Open it up!
秦
Qin.
真有趣  那個丟下我的人現在成了我的救世主
Funny, the man who left me behind is now my savior.
曼達人
Mando.
-哥哥  -妹妹
- Brother! - Sister.
這里馬上就會受到攻擊  他死定了  走吧
Attack's on the way. He's already dead meat. Let's go!
這樣最好
Come on, it's better this way.
活該
You deserve this!
走吧
Let's go!
曼達人  曼達人
Mando. Mando?
我已收到你的信息
I've received your transmission.
你回來后  把獵物直接交給客戶
Upon your return, deliver the quarry directly to the client.
有趣
Interesting.
零  我們找到秦了
Zero, we got Qin.
我找到了曼達洛人的資料
I found some information on The Mandalorian.
來自賞金獵人協會
From the Bounty Hunters Guild.
隨便啦  快讓我們離開飛船
Yeah, do whatever. Just get us off this ship.
你還有10分鐘
You have 10 minutes remaining.
-零呼叫梅菲爾德  -等等  等等
- Zero to Mayfeld. Zero to Mayfeld. - Wait, wait, wait!
-怎么了  -有個隱患
- Yeah? - You have a potential problem.
他逃走了
He has escaped.
-我就說應該干掉他吧  -我知道
- I told you we should've ended him. - I know!
-這是你的錯  -我知道
- This is your fault! - I know!
-走  快  快  -快走
- Go! Go, go, go! - Come on!
-不  -不
- No! - No!
不  伯格  伯格
No! Burg! Burg!
零呼叫梅菲爾德  梅菲爾德  收到嗎
Zero to Mayfeld. Mayfeld, do you copy?
通訊好像失效了
It seems comms are no longer functioning,
所以你聽不見我說話
therefore you cannot hear me.
只能靠你們自己了
You are on your own.
有趣
Curious.
沒關系  你和德瓦隆人分頭行動
It's all right. You and the Devaronian, split up.
找到曼達人  殺了他
Find Mando and kill him.
然后想辦法回飛船
Then find a way back to the ship!
零  幫我們指條路
Zero! We need a path.
零
Zero!
你有名字嗎
Do you have a name?
梅菲爾德
Mayfeld.
梅菲爾德先生  趕緊幫我離開這艘飛船
Well, Mr. Mayfeld, you're gonna get me the hell off this ship.
等等  你妹妹怎么辦
Hey, wait. What about your sister?
什么怎么辦
What about her?
家人關系真棒
Nice family.
曼達人一直很討厭機器人
Mando always did hate droids.
零
Z?
不管蘭恩承諾了什么  我給你三倍
Whatever Ran promised, I'll see to it you get triple share.
抓住他
Just get him.
希望你付得起
You better be good for it.
曼達人
Mando.
你在哪里  小老鼠
Where are you, little mouse?
讓我看看你的臉  曼達洛人
Let's see your face, Mandalorian.
零  他在哪里
Zero, where is he?
什么
What the...
不
No!
秦
Qin.
你殺了其他人
You killed the others.
他們是罪有應得
They got what they deserved.
你殺了我就拿不到錢
You kill me, you don't get your money.
不管蘭恩承諾了什么  我都會給你更多
Whatever Ran promised, I'll make sure you get it, and more.
拜托  曼達人
Come on, Mando.
理智點
Be reasonable.
你是受雇抓獵物的吧
You were hired to do a job, right?
那就抓我吧
So do it.
這不是你的準則嗎
Isn't that your code?
你不是個有榮譽感的人嗎
Aren't you a man of honor?
其他人呢
Where are the others?
不問問題  這是規矩  對吧
No questions asked. That's the policy, right?
沒錯  這就是規矩
Yeah. That is the policy.
我完成了任務
I did the job.
是的  你完成了
Yeah, you did.
就像過去的美好時光
Just like the good old days.
是啊  就像過去的美好時光
Yeah, just like the good old days.
殺了他
Kill him.
這是什么
What's this?
那個混蛋
That bastard.
跟蹤信標有一個清晰信號
I got a clear signal on the tracking beacon.
收到
Copy that.
那是X翼戰機嗎
Are those X-wings?
是的  那絕對是跟蹤信標
Yep. That's definitely a tracking beacon.
看起來他們在發射炮艇機
Looks like they're launching a gunship.
收到  上吧
Copy. Goin' in.
我說了這是個壞主意
I told you that was a bad idea.
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
翻譯     哈里星球    RiverSide152
翻譯     星星與野狗    累
校對     星星與野狗
時間軸     Caroline
后期     累
總監     星星與野狗